《越狱》第四季 第十五集
Prison.Break.S04E15
《越狱》  前情回顾
Previously on Prison Break.
迈克尔
Michael!
"锡拉"是完整的
Scylla is complete.
你这是干什么
What the hell are you doing?!
买家已经在路上了
The buyer is already on the way.
我抓到了一个
Yeah, I got one.
是巴格维尔
It's Bagwell.
根本没有和司法部长的会面  对吧
There is no meeting with the attorney general, is there?
他病了  林肯
He's sick, Lincoln.
就算他们没杀他
If they haven't killed him already...
我们一定会把他救回来  我保证
We'll get him back, I promise.
迈克尔需要手术来去除他
Michael needs an operation to remove a tumor
颞叶上的肿瘤
from his temporal lobe.
条件是  你要把"锡拉"安全找回来
The price of the operation is the safe return of Scylla.
这是什么
What's this?
额外奖励
Added incentive.
出什么事了
What's going on?
迈克尔在哪里
Where's Michael?
迈克尔需要做手术  也会进行
Michael needs surgery; he's gonna get it.
在哪
Where?
-这里  -什么
Here. What?
克兰兹已经安排了世上最好的医生
Krantz has arranged for the best doctors in the world.
我们不能让他们靠近他
We can't let them near him.
我们没时间了
We're out of time.
这是我们唯一的选择
It's our last option.
我不明白为什么"公司"要帮他
I don't understand why the Company would help him.
唐克雷蒂医生  欢迎
Dr. Tancredi, welcome.
请
Please...
没什么好害怕的
there's nothing to be afraid of.
我们只想帮助你们
All we want is to help.
你会救迈克尔吗
You're going to save Michael?
你怀疑我们的能力
You question our capabilities?
不  我怀疑你的目的
No. I'm questioning your motives.
当一个人正遭受痛苦的折磨
When a fellow human being is suffering,
我们为什么不能帮他一把
why would we not want to lend a hand?
同情  莎拉
Empathy, Sara,
这就是我们和野兽不同的地方
it's the only thing that separates us from the beasts.
手术进行的同时
For the duration of the surgery,
你就是我的客人
you'll be treated as a guest in my home.
手术以后呢
And afterwards?
长官  病人准备好了
Sir... the patient is ready.
会没事的  莎拉
It's going to be all right, Sara.
相信我
Trust me.
斯科菲尔德先生  虽然你会被麻醉
Mr. Scofield, although you're going to be anesthetized
而且不会感到任何明显的疼痛
and should feel no significant pain, we will need to keep
但是  我们需要你在手术中保持清醒
you awake for the duration of the procedure.
为安全起见  我们需要一直监视
As a safety precaution, we'll need to continually monitor
你的语言和感知能力  这样才能确定
your speech and sensory activity to insure the tissue
病体被去除的同时  不会给你带来任何后遗症
being removed will not leave you impaired in any way.
这是什么医院
What hospital is this?
不用担心  这有最好的医生
Don't worry about it. You've got some good doctors
为你治疗
who are going to take great care of you.
我要拿回"锡拉"
I have to get Scylla.
不  不
No, no, no, no.
现在不行
Not now.
林肯在哪
Where's Linc?
他也在这
He's here.
他很好
He's just fine.
迈克尔手术完成前  我是不会离开的
I'm not leaving until Michael has his surgery.
如果你不履行我们之间的承诺
And I'm not starting surgery until you prove
我是不会让他们给迈克尔动手术的
you can hold up your end of the deal.
我们说话之际  "锡拉"就离我们越来越远了
Scylla's slipping through our fingers as we speak.
我们和你弟弟都没有时间了
Time is not on our side, nor on your brother's.
你能从我这里
Now, you'll get full cooperation
得到全力支持
from my office.
需要什么帮助  就打这个号码
If you need anything, just call this number.
我要所有关于赛尔夫和格雷琴的信息
I'm gonna need everything you've got on Self and Gretchen.
化名  所有信息
Aliases, whatever you got.
共犯如何
How about an accomplice?
如果你想要
Now, if you're gonna want...
闭嘴
Shut up.
如果你告诉我他们在那里
You can save yourself a lot of pain
你就可以不用受苦
and the embarrassment of begging me to stop
也不用到时求我住手
if you just tell me where they are.
格雷琴和叛徒特工
Gretchen and Agent Turncoat?
是的
Yeah.
这样的情报
Information like that seems like it could be
可是有一定价值的
of a certain intrinsic value.
如果你能答应
If there were offers made,
给我点好处  我认为
carrots dangled, I could see...
我觉得我应该拿点好处
Look, I deserve some kind of something here,
毕竟  我也付出不少心血
all the work I put in.
如果不是我找到惠斯勒的书
If it wasn't for me finding Whistler's bird book then...
你只配给你个机会
The only thing you deserve is the opportunity
保全你的牙齿和手指甲
to keep your teeth and fingernails.
不  你
No. You...
我不会告诉你任何事情
I'm not gonna tell you anything.
我会把你的牙齿一颗颗拔出来
I'm gonna pull out every single tooth, every single one.
怎么样
How about it?
我刚才只是开玩笑
Look, I was just fooling...
好吧
All right!
阿林顿码头  阿林顿码头
Arlington Pier! Arling... Arlington Pier!
什么时候
When? What time?
三点
Three o'clock.
这是最后一针麻醉药
This is the last of the anesthetic
从现在开始  你应该感觉不到任何疼痛  斯科菲尔德先生
From here on out, you shouldn't feel a thing, Mr. Scofield.
我会一直待在那里
I'm going to be right over there the whole time.
我会一直待在这里
I'll be right in here the whole time.
我们准备好了
We're ready.
我不会离开你的
I'm not going to leave you, okay?
你也不准离开我
Don't you dare leave me.
你们小组用过几次伽玛刀治疗
How many surgeries has your team performed using the gamma knife?
伽玛刀治疗
The gamma knife has
有13%的复发率
a recurrence rate of over 13 percent.
我们用的技术更先进
We'll be using a technique that's more advanced.
迈克尔怎么样了
What's going on with Michael?
他们马上要动手术
They're gonna operate.
就这样  他们答应做了
Just like that, they agreed to do that?
我跟他们说迈克尔知道"锡拉"买家是谁
I convinced them Michael knew who was gonna buy Scylla.
我们怎么办
What are we gonna do?
先下手为强
Get our hands on it before they do.
-然后给谁  -我还在想
And give it to who? I'm still working on that.
林肯  我要知道我们要做什么
Linc, I need to know what we're doing.
-我们了结这件事  -真的吗
We finish this! Really?
我倒觉得我们会先完蛋
'Cause it feels like it's finishing us.
你和我  只剩下我们了  兄弟
You, me... we're the only ones left, bro.
再多一天  我们就搞定了
One more day and we're done.
没有你  我做不到
I can't do this without you.
买家来了之后
When the buyer gets here,
由我来谈
why don't you let me do the talking.
为什么
For what?
我策划了整件事情  格雷琴
I engineered this whole thing, Gretchen.
我能自己处理
I can handle my business.
是吗  那你干嘛
Oh, yeah? Why don't you start
不先把你脑门上的汗
by handling that river of nerves
擦干净再说
that's running down your forehead.
你以为这次会更简单吗
Did you think this would be easier?
我想过
I hoped.
但我知道
But I guess I always knew
总会有一大堆尸体出现在面前
it was going to come down to a pile of bodies.
我从不认为你是个杀手
I never pegged you for a killer.
我也从不认为你会是母亲
Yeah, well, I never pegged you for a mom.
你觉得我还能是什么  唐
Is there anything that you'd like to peg me for, Don?
行了  别丢人现眼了
Oh, stop. Okay. Don't embarrass yourself.
对其他人可能有用  但是现在
That may work on everyone else, but right now,
我脑子里只有那1.25亿
the only thing I'm thinking about is that $125 million.
把你的上衣系好  睁大眼睛
So close up your blouse and open your eyes,
因为买家就要来了
because the buyer's on the way.
我可不想他来的时候  我们措手不及
And I don't want any surprises when he gets here.
还要多久
How much longer?
一小时左右  耐心坐着吧
Another hour or so. Just sit tight.
我要上厕所
I need to use the men's room.
好极了
Congratulations.
你以为我想干什么  逃跑
What do you think I'm gonna do, run?
我就是这么想的
That's exactly what I think you're gonna do.
在这你还想让我坐冷板凳吗
You want me to go in the back seat, right here?
你最好能尊重一下
I want you to have a little bit of respect
我的智商  阿历克斯
for my intelligence, Alex.
我尊重你  所以我知道你不会违反
I do, which is why I know you wouldn't violate
法则42-13-72B条  规定了
Code 42-13-72B, which states that an individual
被司法代表押送的个人
being transported by a representative
如果押送时间超过3小时
of the criminal justice system must be afforded the opportunity
必须提供
to relieve himself
上厕所的机会
if the duration of the transport is more than three hours.
我确信有那么长时间了
And I do believe we're creeping up on that time.
好吧  我尽量
All right, I'll see what I can do.
但我也要提醒你一条
But I'm going to remind you of a code.
如果罪犯企图在押送途中逃跑
The one that says if a prisoner attempts escape during transfer,
陪同的特工有权
the accompanying agent has the right to shoot them
在背后开枪射击
through the back of the head.
你确定不想再憋一会吗  阿历克斯
You sure you don't want to hold it, Alex?
我确定
Oh, yeah, I'm sure.
有任何疼痛或不适吗  斯科菲尔德先生
Any pain or discomfort, Mr. Scofield?
没有
No.
那些针  是起稳定作用的吗
Those needles, they're for... stabilization?
不全是  手术期间  迈克尔大脑皮层的
Not exactly. Throughout the surgery, different portions
不同的区域会受到刺激
of Michael's cerebral cortex will be stimulated,
会触发控制
triggering the areas
听觉  嗅觉  记忆的区域
that control senses like hearing, smell, memory.
这就是为什么
That's why some people,
有些人在死之前  经常会说
right before death, often speak of...
人生在眼前一闪而过
Their life flashing before their eyes.
正是
Exactly.
如果大脑缺氧的话
When oxygen is cut off to the brain,
会过度工作  寻找所有资源
it kicks into overdrive, tapping into every resource
以维持身体运作
to continue operating the body.
结果就是  所有感官同时打开
As a result, all of the senses fire off at once.
所有你曾了解  感受  相信过的东西
Everything you've ever known, felt, believed...
都会从眼前闪过
it all passes in a blink of an eye.
你好  迈克尔
Hello Michael
查尔斯
Charles?
我觉得  你现在可以叫我DB了
I guess you can probably call me DB now.
答案是否定的
The answer is no.
答案
The answer?
你在想  你是不是死了
You're wondering if you're dead.
答案是否定的
The answer is no.
那我为什么在这里
Then why am I here?
我相信这是
I believe that's a question
我们都需要寻找的答案
we all need to find the answer to.
看来这是执法史上
This is officially now the most secure bathroom break
最安全的解手时间了
in the history of law enforcement.
确实如此
Yes, it is.
如果你想拷我  堵住所有出口
Hey, look, if you want to cuff me, block off all the exits,
就赶快  如果这样能让你开心的话
take it out and give it a tap, if it makes you happy.
你会开心吗  阿历克斯
Would that make you feel happy, Alex?
我听说监狱能改变人
I hear prison can change a man.
我们能不能赶快做正事
Can we just get this over with.
安全
All clear.
给你15秒
You have 15 seconds.
还行吧
Wasn't so bad now, was it?
你应该相信我
You should've trusted me,
就像我相信你一样
like I trusted you.
好了
All right.
我们可以开始隔离肿瘤了  斯科菲尔德先生
We're ready to begin to isolate the tumor now, Mr. Scofield.
就像我们说过的
As we talked about,
我要你慢慢地背诵字母
I'm going to ask you to slowly recite the alphabet.
如果你想不起字母
If you have any trouble finding a letter,
或说不出字母
any problem saying a letter,
就告诉我们  好吗
you let us know. All right?
好的
All right.
Okay.
准备好了吗
Ready?
开始
And begin.
对不起  查尔斯
I'm sorry, Charles.
为什么
For what?
一切
For everything.
我所说过的谎言
For all the lies I told.
我所造成的痛苦
For all the pain I caused.
你是在寻求我的宽恕吗
Are you asking for forgiveness?
我觉得我不配得到宽恕
I'm not sure I'm entitled to it.
我觉得这由不得
I guess that's for a power
我们决定  不是吗
higher than us to decide, isn't it?
我只是无法相信  我们输了
It's just hard... hard to believe we've lost,
一切都白费了
that it was all for nothing.
可以不必这样
It doesn't have to be.
看来
It looks like
肿瘤长到海马体后面了
the tumor is nestled behind the hippocampus.
你知道答案  迈克尔
You have the answers, Michael.
问题是什么
What are the questions?
我不知道  但你知道
I don't know, but you do.
你只是还没有意识到
You just haven't realized it yet.
前面右转
Up here, make a right.
不  左转
No, no, left, left, left.
我们还有10分钟  你觉得呢
We got ten minutes, what do you think?
有点紧
It's gonna be tight.
他们随时会来
All right, any minute now.
没看到他
There's no sign of him.
查一下怀肯的掌上电脑
Check Vikan's PDA.
看看买家有没有留消息
See if the buyer left him a message.
这个东西坏了
Oh, this thing is broken.
肯定是他摔倒时砸坏了
It must have cracked when he hit the ground.
还能看见号码吗
Can you still see the contact number?
可以  是迈阿密的区号
Yeah, it's a Miami area code.
读一下  我记到我手机里
Okay, read it out. I'll put it in mine.
不  我不会读给你的
No, no, I'm not reading out anything.
我暂时保留这个号码
I'm gonna keep that number
你不介意的话
for now, if you don't mind.
是谁
Who is it?
我姐姐
It's my sister.
不许接
Don't answer it.
我说了不许接
I said don't answer it.
开枪吧
Shoot me.
喂
Hello?
我们自由了
We're free.
他走了
He's gone.
什么
What?
那个
The... the guy
有只假手的人  他放了我们
with the, uh, fake hand... he let us go,
所以我们穿过街  跑到普特的屋子里
so we, uh... we ran across the street to the Patels' house,
几分钟之后  我往窗外看
and a couple minutes later, I looked out the window,
看到
and I saw these, uh...
两个人
these two guys in, uh...
穿着西服  把他拖进货车了
in these suits, and they, uh, dragged him off
行了  格雷琴  让巴格维尔接电话
into some van. All right, Gretchen, put Bagwell on the phone.
-他不在那  -格雷琴  我可没开玩笑
He's not there. Gretchen, I'm not playing anymore...
唐  "公司"的人抓住他了
Don, the Company took him.
艾米丽怎么样了
How's Emily?
她没事
She's... She's fine.
听着  格雷琴
Listen, Gretchen.
你得离我们远点
You need to stay away from us.
为了所有的人
For everyone's sake.
给  宝贝
Here, baby.
再见  阿姨
Bye, Auntie.
别管巴格维尔那个乡巴佬
Forget that hick, Bagwell.
不  不行
No, I can't.
他知道交易地点
He knows the location of the exchange.
如果他知道我们在这
If he knows we're here...
那么"公司"也知道
then the Company does, too.
那就是
Hey, that's it.
就在那  阿林顿码头
Right there-- Arlington Pier.
靠边停
Pull over.
血  兄弟
Blood, papi.
我们刚刚错过了
We just missed them.
我去附近看看
I'll go look around.
指挥部
Operations.
将军说  如果有需要就打这个电话
The General said to call this number if I needed help.
请说您的通行码
Your clearance code, please.
通行码
Clearance code?
我是林肯・布伦斯  你将失去"锡拉"如何
How about I'm Lincoln Burrows and you're about to lose Scylla?
通过
Proceed.
我要追踪这条线
I need to trace this line.
我们试过了
We've already tried.
你所在的区域
You're in a zone
无法进行视频监控
where visual surveillance is an impossibility.
那就在区域外
Well, how about you look
查找过去15分钟内
outside the zone and check for a vehicle leaving
离开的车辆
in the last 15 minutes.
如果有  核对一下  再给我电话
If you see one, get a match and call me.
没发现
Nothing.
没有痕迹  不过我找到这些
No tracks, but I found these.
他们知道我们在找他们
They know we're onto them.
我们要在他们分开前找到他们
We got to find these people before they split.
有人在  但不是卖方
Someone's here, but it's not the seller.
我该怎么做
What do you want me to do?
我只是很好奇  朗格
I'm just curious, Lang.
你什么时候决定背叛我的
When did you decide to turn your back on me?
估计在你决定
Probably about the same time
变成逃犯的同时吧
you decided to become a fugitive.
我没跟你说话
I wasn't talking to you.
我立过誓要维护法律  阿历克斯
I took an oath to uphold the law, Alex.
为了升职吗
Did you do it for a promotion?
为了抓我  他们答应你什么了
Did they promise you anything to serve me up?
我只想让你安全  阿历克斯
The only thing I ever wanted was your safety, Alex.
你逃跑时间越长
The longer you're on the run,
我实现目标的机会就越少
the lower my chance of getting what I want.
你往外看什么  阿历克斯
What you looking for out there, Alex?
那里
There.
我是惠勒特工  有个嫌疑犯
Agent Wheeler. I've got a suspect
在拘禁期间逃跑
fleeing custody off Route 14
格林伯格以南3公里14号公路
about three miles north of Greenburg.
请求空中支援
Requesting backup and air support.
我不是有意吓你
I didn't mean to startle you.
你在这干什么
What are you doing here?
客户服务
Customer service.
质量控制
Quality control.
我希望能掌控一切
I like to keep a hand in all our theaters of engagement.
说得就像个军人
Spoken like a military man.
把人命看得跟演戏一样简单
So easy to discuss lives in the balance when it's just theater.
我很欣赏你的忠诚  莎拉
I admire your devotion, Sara.
我最看重这个
It's an attribute I value above all others,
但我想知道
but I wonder...
你忠诚的是信仰
is it the cause
还是这个人
you believe in or the man?
我是说  你是个空想家呢
I mean, are you an ideologue
或者只是个难得有人垂青就死缠烂打
or just a silly schoolgirl following the brooding boy
的傻女学生
who finally noticed her?
我是个寻找
I'm the girl whose father was murdered,
谋杀我父亲的混蛋的女生
who's looking for the bastard responsible.
你希望我打几个电话
Would you like me to make a few phone calls,
看能否帮你
see if I can point you
指点迷津
in the right direction?
你放心  他接受的
You can relax, he's receiving
是最好的治疗
the best possible care.
是吗
Is he?
因为我从没看到这种仪器
Because I've never seen this equipment before,
也从没见过这种方式
and I've never seen this procedure.
这是实验性的  对吗
It's experimental, isn't it?
可以这么说  但以前用过一次
Well, you could say that, but it has been used once before.
那个病人活了多久
How long did the patient live?
唐克雷蒂医生
Dr. Tancredi,
我知道你怎么看我们的做法  但是记住
I know your opinion of the work we do here, but know this.
要看事情的本质
Not everything is as it seems.
而且  这个手术
And for what it's worth,
让那个病人过得很好  很久
the patient lived a long, happy life.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
结构工程师的责任是
It is the job of a structural engineer
让他所有创造的东西
to make sure everything he creates is designed
能承受附加在上面的重量
to withstand the weight placed upon it.
我在这建造的
What I've built here...
不够牢固
does not hold up.
如果你发现
If you discovered
你建造的东西有缺陷
that a structure you built was deficient,
你会拆了它
would you tear down the building
还是设法修整它
or find a way to fix it?
我试过修整
I've tried to fix it.
我试过让事情按部就班
I've tried to make things right.
但我做的只是加大重量
All I've done is add more weight to it.
现在
And now...
我也承受不住了
...now I can't take anymore.
我想做的只是救我哥哥
All I wanted to do was save my brother's life.
你做到了吗
Did you do that?
是的
Yes...
但是有多少人
but how many other people
为了这件事而失去生命
lost their lives in the process?
现在知道了
Knowing that now,
你还会让他死吗
would you have let him die?
不会
No.
因此你觉得自己是个杀人凶手吗
And that makes you feel like some kind of murderer?
可能吧
Perhaps.
杀十个人  你是个连环杀手
Take ten lives, you're a serial killer.
杀一千个人  你就是战争英雄
Take thousands, you're a war hero.
这不是战争
This isn't war.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
只不过是"公司"的小黑名单而已
There's nothing more than the Company's little black book.
名字  数字  行动报告
Names, numbers, operation reports.
事情不能只看表面  迈克尔
Not everything is as it seems, Michael.
但你知道
But you know that...
不是吗
don't you?
好了  我们得和买家
All right, look, we need to reestablish contact
重新取得联系  告诉他发生了什么事
with the buyer, explain to him what happened,
重新选个交易地点
and then set a new location for the exchange.
我得说
I got to say...
我很惊讶  唐
I'm amazed at you, Don.
那么长时间  你从没想过了解
Yeah, all this time, and you never once asked to see
-"锡拉"里的信息  -因为我不在乎信息
the information in Scylla. That's 'cause I don't care
我只关心它的价值
about the information; I just care what it's worth.
也许你担心  要是知道里面的信息后
Maybe you're just worried if you actually knew what was on it,
你会想  买家是什么样的人
you'd have second thoughts about who you're selling it to.
喂
Hello?
布伦斯先生  我们有目标的情况
Mr. Burrows, we have a hit on the targets.
路况监视器显示他们进了一家便利店
Traffic camera picked them up entering a convenience store
在威利街14号
on Valley and 14th.
看来他们留下蛛丝马迹了
Looks like they left a footprint.
不许动
Don't move.
干得不错  朗格特工
That's a hell of a job, Agent Lang.
是你教我如何看穿
You're the one who taught me how to read the mind
逃犯的思想  记得吗
of a convict on the run, remember?
如果你把我带走  我就是死路一条
If you take me in, I'm as good as dead.
你知道的
You know that.
所以
So...
我现在要逃走了
I'm gonna run now.
如果你要阻拦我
And if you need to stop me,
你就必须杀掉我
you're gonna have to shoot.
别逼我
Don't make me do this.
对不起
I'm sorry.
他时他方再见  费丽舍
Another time, another place, eh, Felicia?
我会扣下扳机
I will pull this trigger.
发生什么了
What happened?
他跑了
He got away.
你看到他了吗
Did you have him?
我
Uh, yeah, I...
我以为看到他了
I thought I had him unless I...
但是跟丢了
I just missed.
你看到他往哪跑了吗
Did you see which way he went?
还是连这个也跟丢了
Or did you just miss that, too?
他朝东去了
He went east.
-伙计  -怎么了
Hey, buddy. What's up?
我在找一名高个黑色头发的女人
I'm looking for a, a tall chick with black hair
一个男人  高个
and a guy-- tall guy, uh...
看上去就像波仔小丑
He looks like Bozo the clown.
你知道波仔和埃尔韦拉吗
You know, Bozo and Elvira?
你们
You guys
是警察还是什么
cops or somethin'?
不是
Not even close.
有印象吗
So how 'bout it?
我不记得见过这些人
I don't remember anyone like that.
现在呢  臭小子
How 'bout now, you punk?
-现在呢  -好的  我说
-How 'bout now?! -Okay! Okay!
他们买了个手机
They bought a phone, man.
给我收据
I want the receipt.
好的
All right.
他们在路上
On their way.
你知道买家是谁吗
You have any idea who the buyer is?
不知道  也永远不会知道
No. And we never will.
任何想盗取"锡拉"里的信息的人
Whoever's walking away with the information that's on Scylla
都会不惜一切
will do whatever it takes
避开公司的雷达
to stay below The Company radar.
而且  你要是搞了别人的老婆
Besides, would you screw some guy's wife
会把名片放在他的枕头上吗
and then leave your card on his pillow?
你不就是这么对将军的嘛
Isn't that what you just did to the General?
说嘛
Come on.
我们经历了这么多
After all we've been through,
就不能互相坦诚吗
we can't be honest with each other?
你的小照片
Your little photo shoot.
还有想偷第6张卡的馊主意
And your weak ass attempt at the sixth card.
你就想让他知道你参与了  对吧
You wanted him to know you were involved, right?
说吧  他惩罚过你
Come on. He punished you,
对待垃圾一样对你  就像你父亲那样
treated you like crap-- just like your real daddy.
你希望至少其中一人付出代价  不是吗
You want at least one of them to pay for it, right?
说吧  格雷琴
Come on, Gretchen.
我了解你
I-I know you.
我查了很多资料
I did my homework.
天啊  唐  你
Gee, Don, you...
你完全挖出了我的恋父情结啊  厉害
you just cracked my whole Electra complex wide open.Kudos.
但并不是只有你一个人查了资料
But you're not the only one who did their homework.
只是想让你知道
Just so you know.
-是吗  你还想说什么  -现在
-Yeah? You got something to say? -Right now,
我们得为即将来临的一切做好准备
we need to be ready for whatever's coming.
你最好眼观六路  唐
You better watch your six, Don.
好的
Okay.
-你找我吗  -是的
-You wanted to see me? -Yeah.
我从显示器上没看明白
I-I can't quite tell from the monitors,
但我觉得那个肿瘤
but from what I can see, the-the growth,
看起来并不只是在下丘脑
it looks like it isn't just on the hypothalamus.
我知道这只是初步诊断
I understand that was the initial diagnosis,
但是进入里面后  发现也扩散到
but once we got in there, it appears to have spread
海马体了
to the hippocampus as well.
好的
Okay. Um,
如果肿瘤切除后  会丧失记忆吗
so with the removal, will there be any memory loss?
像这种情况
Well, in cases like this,
有小部分组织必须移除
where small portions have to be removed,
但基本不会影响到大部分记忆
it hardly ever affects what's referred to as "net memory."
我们将一生的经历
We're all tapped into such small portions
都储存在这一小部分
of what we've experienced in our lifetime.
大部分只是储存在里面
The bulk of it's just kept in storage,
很少被意识所承认
rarely acknowledged by the conscious mind.
所以即使有部分记忆丧失
So while there may be some gross memory loss,
他也不会知道
he won't ever know it's gone.
因为他根本不知道那些记忆的存在
Because he'll never know it was there.
护士
Nurse?
血压在下降  90/60
BP's dropping, 90/60.
怎么回事
What's going on?
我不知道
I don't know.
把多巴胺的输液速度调到12.5
Increase dopamine delivery rate to 12.5.
时机成熟了  我们再用"交易"
We'll use the Bargain when the time is right.
现在就是最好的时机
The time is now.
"交易"  "交易"
Bargain. Bargain.
时机成熟  再用
We'll use time--  time is right.
时机成熟了  我们再用"交易"
We'll use the Bargain when the time is right.
或许现在就是最好的时机
perhaps the time is now.
脑电图达到峰值
EEG's spiking.
大脑活动异常
Brain activity's all over the place.
动脉压值55
MAP's at 55.
血压不稳定  在下降
BP's erratic. Dropping.
85  84
85, 84.
给他注射1毫升阿托品  迈克尔
Give him one mil of Atropine. Michael?
能听见我们说话吗
Are you still with us?
由世上最聪明的人设计出的安全系统
The best minds in the world designed this system,
你几乎把它打破了
and you almost beat it.
但只要我们有
But as long as we have...
...we have-- as long as we...
你听说
So what are you hearing, uh,
锡拉价值多少
Scylla's worth?
我听说值上百万
Me, I'm hearing millions.
前几天
Things have happened
发生的事
in the past few days that
让我感觉不安
have made me uneasy.
但只要我们有"锡拉"  我们就有"力量"
But as long as we have Scylla,  we have power.
很抱歉  迈克尔
I'm sorry, Michael.
他快不行了  78  急救
We're losing him. 78. Get the crash cart.
-喉镜  得插管  -不
Laryngeal scope. we need to intubate. No.
怎么了
What's going on?
该走了
It's time to go.
迈克尔
Michael?
Michael?!
迈克尔  怎么回事  他怎么会这样
Michael! What's going on? Why's he crashing?
唐克雷蒂小姐  你不能
Ms. Tancredi, you cannot...
没事  没关系
No, it's okay.
迈克尔  别这样
Michael, don't do this.
不要这样
Don't do this.
不要离开
Don't go.
我们还没完成呢
We're not finished with this.
还没完成呢
Not finished yet.
迈克尔  对不起
Michael, I'm sorry.
是时候了
It's time.
求你了  查尔斯
Please, Charles.
迈克尔  别这样
Michael, not like this.
别这样
Not like this.
不能这样
It doesn't happen like this.
你答应过我要一起完成的
You promised me we would finish together.
没关系
It's okay.
你已经完成了你该做的
You've done your part.
我还没弄明白呢
I haven't figured it out yet!
你已经弄明白了
Yes, you have.
你能做点什么吗
Would you do something?
我在努力
I'm trying!
放松点
Relax.
你可能认为这不好
You might think it's bad,
实际上不是的
but it's not.
死亡
Dying?
不是
No!
不要放弃
Don't give up.
事情不能只看表面
Not everything is as it seems.
再见  迈克尔
Good-bye, Michael.
查尔斯
Charles.
迈克尔
Michael?
迈克尔  不要离开我
Michael, don't leave me.
你也不准离开我
Don't you dare leave me.
莎拉
Sara.
公司追踪了收据上的序列号
Company tracked the serial code off the receipt.
格雷琴五分钟前打了一个电话
Gretchen just placed a call five minutes ago
-序列号相符  -在哪打的
matching the tracking number. From where?
两英里外
Two miles away.
据我所知  你们应该有三个人
I was told there'd be three of you.
现在没有了
Well there aren't.
你拿了钱吗  那么小的盒子
You have the money? Because that's a small case
-可装不了1.25亿  -我们不用现金交易
for $125 million... We don't deal in cash.
一旦我确定东西是真的
Once I verify the validity of the item,
钱就会打到你提供的账户上
the funds will be wired to an account number you provide.
请把东西拿出来
The item, please.
不行  我看不到钱
No, no, no, you're not gonna see the item
你就不能看东西
until I see the money, okay? You'll have to
恕我不能相信一个有几个按钮的亮盒子
forgive me if I don't trust a shiny case with some buttons.
我要确定数据是否完整
I need to confirm that the data is intact.
不然的话  你手里的东西
Without it, the item you possess
不过也就是个靓盒子
is nothing more than a fancy box.
谈到这点
Speaking of...
把东西给他
Give this man the item.
不  我谁也不给
No, I'm not giving anyone...
他是个商人
This is a businessman
在做商务交易
making a business transaction.
你拖的时间越长
One with the longer you take,
我们就越危险
the more danger you put us all in.
你能读出里面的数据吗
Can you read what's on there?
最好是这样
You better hope so.
他们不会轻易把锡拉给我们的
They're not just gonna give us Scylla.
你应该明白吧
You know what that means, right?
我们分头行动
Let's split up.
看上去不像"公司"的黑名单
That doesn't look like a company's black book.it's...
更像是
It looks more like a...
我确信你们明白
I'm sure you understand
不能让人知道"锡拉"的去向
no one can know where Scylla's going to.
算你走运  甜心
It's your lucky day, sugar.
你可不走运
Not yours.
放下枪
Drop it.
看住她
Cover her.
-他在哪  -我不知道
Where is he? I don't know.
他在哪
Where is he?
-我不知道  -跑了
I don't know!  Gone.
"锡拉"被偷了
Stolen.
谁干的
By who?
谁
我要是死了  你永远都别想知道
If I die... you'll never know.
你真漂亮
You look beautiful.
撒谎
You're a liar.
怎么样了
How'd it go?
他们还在做一些测试
They're still running some tests,
不过他们确信已经搞定了
but they feel pretty confident they got it all.
这是哪
And what is this place?
你得了解一下你的手术
You need to know something about your surgery.
手术是"公司"的医生做的
It was performed by Company doctors,
将军安排了这一切
and the General made all the arrangements.
为什么
Why?
我不知道
I don't know.
林肯在处理这件事
Lincoln's handling it.
他说他有个计划
He says he has a plan.
说实话  我唯一关心的
I'll be honest. Right now, you're alive,
就是现在你还活着
and that's all I care about.
你肯定会笑的  我做了个有关"锡拉"的梦
You're gonna laugh, but I had a dream about Scylla.
我们了解的只是赛尔夫的片面之词
The only thing we really know about it is what Self told us.
你需要休息
You need to rest.
我是认真的
I'm serious.
如果它不只是"公司"的黑皮书呢
What if it's not just the Company's little black book?
万一是
What if it's...
事情不能只看表面
Not everything is as it seems.
别的什么呢
...something more?
比如
Like what?
一些好的东西
Something good.
为什么要费这么大周折
Why go to so much trouble
保护过去的信息
to protect information about the past,
"公司"随时都可以
information the Company could just delete
删除这些信息
any time they wanted to?
将军说
The General said...
只要我们有"锡拉"  我们就有"力量"
As long as we have Scylla, we have power.
我认为他说的力量
I don't think he was talking about power
并不是控制或影响
like control or influence.
我觉得他说的是能源
I think he was talking about energy.
硼
Boron.
氩
Argon.
镓
Gallium.
铟
Indium.
交易
Bargain.
理论上而言  如果有办法
There's a theory that if you can find a way
把这些元素结合到太阳能电池设计中
to combine these elements into the design of a solar cell,
就能百分之百地利用太阳能
you can harness 100% of the sun's energy.
一旦拥有这种能量
With that kind of power,
没有什么是不可能的
possibilities are limitless.
这就是为什么"锡拉"会受到重重保护
It would certainly explain all the security around Scylla.
他们不是保护过去
They're not protecting the past.
而是为了保护未来
They're protecting the future.
真不知道还有什么
Wonder what else is on it.
我是说  他们为你提供的医疗设备
I mean, the equipment you were treated with,
还有药物
and the drugs they gave you.
都是在公共市场买不到的
none of it exists on the open market.
所以才会有人愿意
Which would explain why some people are willing
支付数百万以获得"锡拉"
to pay hundreds of millions to get their hands on Scylla.
他们不是为了搞垮"公司"
It's not about taking down the Company.
而是
It's about
想成为"公司"
becoming the Company.
他们想了解一切
It's about knowing what they know,
控制一切
controlling what they know.
我们该怎么办
What do we do now?
下一步计划是什么
So, what's the next move?
我先去看迈克尔
I'm gonna check on Michael.
不  我是说  在那之后
No, I mean, after that.
我是说  "锡拉"在某处
I mean, Scylla's out there somewhere.
我们真的要继续寻找它的下落吗
Are we really gonna keep chasing it?
我不知道  以后再说
I don't know. We'll figure it out later.
不
No.
我不会来了  林肯
I won't be here, Linc.
我不能再这么做了
I can't do it anymore.
莎拉说迈克尔已经没事了
Sara said Mike was okay,
我只关心这个问题
and that's all I needed to know.
但是我有自己的生活
But now I got to go live my life.
不用整天看见别人死去
And that's a life where I can go a day without seeing
甚至自己都死了
a dead body, or-or almost becoming one.
我不是想逃避  哥们
I'm not running away, papi.
我只是想继续生活
I'm-I'm just... I'm just moving on.
这本来就与你无关
This was never about you.
你为我们做的一切
Everything you did, you did for us.
我此生难忘
I'll never forget that.
我知道
I know you got
你有要事在身
something cooking, so...
无论如何  小心点  好吗
whatever it is, just be careful, okay?
好
Yeah.
谢谢
Thank you.
等你和迈克尔安顿下来
And when you and Mike get down below
开一家冲浪店
and open that surf shop...
潜水店
Scuba shop.
要招人时记得叫我
Maybe there will be a job there for me.
没问题
You can count on it.
你知道谁拿走了"锡拉"吗
Do you know who took it?
不  但赛尔夫和格雷琴知道
No, but Self and Gretchen do.
好
Good.
你有合作伙伴了
Then you've got your team.
我不会为他们卖命的
I'm not working for them.
我得对我的命令
You'll work with a basset hound in a birthday hat
唯命是从
if that's what I tell you to do.
这是一个雇员的职责所在
That's what being an employee means.
你必须接受命令并全力以赴
You're determined and dedicated.
但是你简历中的空白
But there are holes in your resume
格雷琴或赛尔夫  甚至巴格维尔都能填补
that Gretchen or Self or even Bagwell can fill.
你们都从我这儿拿了东西
Now, you all took something from me,
你们必须物归原主
and you're all going to get it back.
而且
Besides...
你一个人是搞不定的
you can't handle this by yourself.
我觉得你应该知道
And deep down, I think you know that.
让他们在外面等我吧
Have them meet me outside.
谁知道呢
Who knows?
你可能会喜欢上这里
You may find that you like it here.
怪事接踵而至
Stranger things have happened.
在你家都发生过
They've certainly happened in your family.
现在
Now,
关于迈克尔
about Michael.
你会告诉他吗
Are you going to tell him,
还是我去
or should I?
你拿到了吗
Do you have it?
拿到了
In my hand.
好  你知道该怎么做
Good. You know what to do.
我上次去医院看你
Last time I saw you in a hospital,
是在少年棒球队时  你弄伤了胳膊
you busted your arm in Little League.
是的  滑二垒时
Yeah, some bruiser knocked me down
几条大汉把我撩倒了
sliding into second.
真遗憾
Sorry about that.
但你恢复得很好  对吧
But you healed good, though, right?
是的
Yeah.
这次也一样
This will, too.
无论你有什么计划
Look, whatever plan you're working on
把我们从这弄出去  我们最好有所行动
to get us out of here, we better make a move on it.
你出不去了  迈克尔
You're not getting out of here, Michael.
什么意思
What do you mean?
我做了个交易
I made a deal.
用"锡拉"换回你的命
Your life in exchange for Scylla.
你为什么这么做
Why would you do that?
就像当初你刺满纹身
Same reason you covered your body in tattoos
入狱救我一样
and-and broke into Fox River.
这事不仅关乎你我
This is not just about us...
就是我们的事  一直如此
That's exactly who it's about. It's all it's ever been about.
我们为"公司"摆平这件事
We do this one thing for the Company,
然后我们重获新生
then they set us up for life.
你真的相信他们吗
And you actually trust them?
我还能信谁
Who else am I gonna trust?
政府  唐・赛尔夫那种人
The government? Guys like Don Self?
我不想再看到挚爱亲朋离去  迈克尔
I'm done watching loved ones and friends die, Michael.
"锡拉"并非我们所想的那样
Scylla isn't what we thought it was.
-完全不同  -我不在乎
Not even close. I don't care.
我不明白你怎么这么说
I don't understand how you can say that.
因为唯一值得打拼的是家庭
'Cause the only thing worth fighting for is family.
我会尽一切努力结束这一切
I'm gonna do everything and anything I can to end this,
你  我  所有人
so you, me, all of us
才能继续我们的生活
can get on with our lives.
就凭你对"公司"的了解
You think you can do that
你以为你能做到吗
knowing what you know about the Company?
你想知道我对公司的了解吗
You want to know what I know about the Company?
妈妈生前一直为他们卖命
Mom worked for them before she died.
我只是继承家族事业
I'm just moving on in the family business.
林肯  别这么做
Linc, don't do this.
已经说定了
It's done.
林肯  林肯
Linc? Linc!